Gregory Kelleher

+353 (0)86 3690234 gregory@gregorykelleher.com

gregorykelleher.com github.com/gregorykelleher linkedin.com/in/gregorykelleher

Summary

I'm a Computer Science undergraduate, currently in my final year at Maynooth University. My interests lie across web development and embedded systems - the world of IoT.

This is most evident in my two recent internships at Intel R&D where I worked as part of the IoT Group for a combined total of 10 months. Outside of Intel, I maintain a website hosted on my own VPS, where I blog on what I'm doing. I also freelance, developing many websites and prototypes for clients over the last 4 years, most of which are hosted on my server too.

Education is a personal motivation and is visible in my volunteer work at CoderDojo as well as my time as a class instructor for CTY Ireland. I've also presented at Dublin Maker Faire with my university and more recently attended the Workday intervarsity Hack-a-thon.

Experience

Intel Research & Development Ireland Ltd / Software Engineer

FEB 2017 - AUG 2017, LEIXLIP

Intern working as part of the Strategy and Solutions Engineering Division (SSED). Conducted study into the role for Information Security in relation to IoT. Special focus into Direct Anonymous Attestation (DAA) algorithms, as well as cryptographic protocols such as TLS/SSL.

Familiarity with OpenSSL and implementing TLS/SSL best practices, e.g. HSTS, HPKP, ECDHE, HTTP/2, OCSP stapling, forward secrecy .etc

Intel Research & Development Ireland Ltd / Software Engineer

MAY 2016 - SEPT 2016, LEIXLIP

Summer internship working with embedded systems and microcontrollers as part of Quark Solutions Division (QSD). Built proficiency in C with GNU toolchain, alongside debugging tools such as GDB and OpenOCD, as well as VCS (Git and Gerrit).

Centre for Talented Youth Ireland / Educator

JAN 2016 - MARCH 2016 / JAN 2017 - MARCH 2017

Class Educator leading a class of 20 students for 3 months. Taught electronics and embedded programming using Intel Galileo microcontrollers.

Designed and delivered on my own course-work, including practical experiments building electronic circuits and creating embedded projects. My notes and slides can be found on my website here">here.

Invited back in 2017 to teach again for a further 3 months. That course was based upon teaching students computer gaming using GameMaker software and tools.

Freelancing / Personal

AUG 2015 - PRESENT

I've often done freelance work to develop and build progressive web applications and websites for clients through the years. Taking on side projects has enabled me to further build upon my technical skills, as well as providing an avenue for me to experiment with new technologies.

Most, if not all my work has been hosted on my own personal server and I frequently work to improve on my work. Documentation can also be found on my <u>website</u> and <u>Github</u> (@gregorykelleher) account.

Proficiencies

- Web
 - JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, HTML5/SCSS
 - AngularJS, Ionic, Firebase, Grav CMS
 - NGINX: performance, optimisation config .etc
- Embedded
 - o C/C++
 - o Intel QMSI, Libmraa
 - o GCC, GDB, GNU Make, OpenOCD
 - o Intel D2000, C1000, Galileo, Edison, Arduino .etc
- Tools
 - o Git, Gerrit, Vim, Bash, GNU/Linux, GPG, DigitalOcean

Education

 $\textbf{Maynooth University} \, / \, \text{B.Sc. Computer Science and Software Engineering} \,$

SEPT 2014 - MAY 2018

First Class Honours 3rd Year - Grade Breakdown upon request.

Recent college project - demo - github

Member of Computer Science Society

Sligo Grammar School / Leaving Certificate

SEPT 2008 - MAY 2014

References

Peter Barry / Senior Principal Engineer / Intel R&D

Upon Request

Mike Hibbett / Senior IoT Software Architect / Intel R&D

Upon Request